Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services, MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 15 years and
today I am presenting to you Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
launched a new pure term plan in June 2025, named Super Term Plan,
in this plan you can get health management services up to ₹ 46,000 for free,
in this policy you will get insurance in increasing order,
options for return and premium are also given and many more benefits and features
will be available in this policy, watch this video completely and if you like the video, then
definitely like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS where you
will find more than 300 insurance related videos and you will find videos on more than 60 term plans
which
will help in financial planning insurance planning and if you want to purchase the policy, then I have given the link below in the description,
by clicking on which you can purchase the policy, in this policy you are
given three options, there is an option of level cover That is, the insurance cover you have
will remain the same through out the policy term. Suppose you have taken an insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore. Through
out the policy term, whatever number of years you have purchased, your insurance cover
will remain Rs. 1 crore. In case of an unfortunate event, your nominees will get one crore. The second option
you will get is of increasing insurance cover. Where your
insurance cover will increase from the first year at a simple interest rate of 5%. Suppose if your insurance cover is Rs. 1 crore, then
your insurance cover will increase by Rs. 55 lakhs every year. Maximum, this
will go up to two years for you. That is, whatever the vested sum assured is, your insurance cover will be double of that.
And in the year in which the unfortunate event occurs,
the nominee will get the increased insurance cover. The third option given in this policy is of return of
premium. If you want to get back all the premiums paid in the policy
as a return of premium, if nothing happens to you in that case, then
you can select this option as well. The premiums for all three will be different
to enhance your coverage. Different cover benefits are also provided in this, in which terminal illness
benefit is also available, that is, if any critical disease occurs which
is difficult to cure and the doctor writes in writing that the patient
may die within six months, then in that case,
you will get terminal illness benefit up to 50% of your sum assured or maximum ₹ 1 crore. In this policy, you
can also take cover for disabilities and along with that you can also take benefit of accelerated critical illness.
I repeat again, this is not critical illness,
it is accelerated critical illness where you will get benefit of 42 illnesses. Accelerated critical illness means
that suppose you took an insurance cover of 1 crore and you
took accelerated critical illness of ₹ 25 lakh, suppose you took cover of ₹ 1 lakh for 42 illnesses,
now any one of the 25 If a major illness is diagnosed for you, suppose you
get cancer or heart attack, then you will get a full ₹25 lakh and now this ₹1
crore - 25 lakh will be your death benefit and in future when you die, you will get ₹75 lakh.
Normally, the additional critical illness rider benefit is a cover above your base
cover. So here, suppose you have a cover of 1 crore, you
have a critical illness of 25 lakhs and you get a critical illness, you get 25 lakhs. Even later,
your insurance cover of 1 crore continues.
There is a slight difference in the premium of both these benefits. Accelerated is a little cheaper.
In the Super Term Plan of Aitya Birla Sun Life Insurance, you are given three options of depth benefit,
where if there is death, the nominee can take the entire amount in lump sum.
Suppose the insurance is of 1 crore, then the entire 1 crore can be taken in lump sum.
The second option is that In Lumpsum, if you don't want to take the entire money at once but
want to earn it as income, that is, you
want to earn ₹1 crore as income every year or every month for the next 10 years or want to earn income for 15 years or want to earn income for 20 years,
if you select the income option, then your premium
will be slightly less than lumpsum because now the company does not have to pay ₹1 crore at once, they
have to pay the money in installments. The third option you will get is Income and Lumpsum. If you feel that some money
should come as income or you should get some lumpsum, then you
can also select this percentage, which is between 10% to 90%, you can select income.
You can also select the remaining amount as lumpsum. It should be in the gap of 10%, that is, 10%
20% 40% 50% 45 55 It cannot be done this way Now let's talk about the features that
you are getting in this policy First of all, waiver of premium, if you
suffer total and permanent disability in an accident or a terminal illness,
in both the cases your premiums will be waived and your insurance cover will continue
In this policy, you are getting 42% critical illness benefit, which you
can take a cover of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 50 lakh I think there is also enhanced life stage production cover,
which is called life stage benefit, where suppose you are unmarried, when you
get married, at that time you can get up to 50% of your insurance or a maximum of Rs 50 lakh cover,
up to Rs 25 lakh on the birth of the first child or up to 25% on the birth of the check-in child, you can also get 25% or
maximum of Rs 25 lakh and 50% of home loan, by taking 50% off base sum in home loan or
a cover of up to Rs 50 lakh If you want to increase your insurance cover, you can do so.
In this policy, you will get early exit benefit, that is, technically you
can call it return of premium or technically you
want to surrender the entire amount and take back the entire money or zero cost which many people call term plan. This
is a feature where you will be able to exercise this feature only after the completion of the minimum policy term of 30 years
and you will not be able to do this in the last 5 years of the policy term,
so technically you will get this benefit only when the policy term is 36 years or more.
Cover continuation benefit
is also given to you in this policy, that is, if due to any reason you are not
able to pay the premium in any one year, you are facing difficulty, then inform the company 30 days in advance that
I will not be able to pay the premium in this financial year, but in the next financial year
I will pay the premium of both the next financial year and this financial year,
so during this period also, in the year in which you are not paying the premium, your
insurance cover will continue and if any unfortunate event occurs If the event happens,
the nominee will get the benefit of the entire insurance cover. Here you are given another good option
that you can change by premium payment. At least
you have paid one premium and suppose you have taken regular premium payment policies where you have
to pay premium for 25, 30, 40 years. After two to four years, you feel that
my financial condition is good now and I can pay premium in limited pay,
then you can change it. If you want to change from regular to limited pay, you
can do it. Instant payment on claim: If you register the claim with the company,
then within one day of registration, if your insurance cover
is between ₹50 lakh to 1 crore, then you will get instant claim up to ₹1 lakh and if your insurance
cover is ₹1 crore or more, then you will get instant claim amount up to ₹ lakh.
The rest of the claim will be approved after the approval. But if the claim is rejected, then the
instant claim you have received will be returned to you by the company. If you are salaried or
female, then you will get this policy at a little discount, you
will get the policy at a slightly cheaper rate and in this you will get health management service up to 46,000 which
is free of cost, which you will get for 20 years for 20 policy term, in this you
can consult related to nutrition, you can take advice from health courses, you can
take consultation, you can get health checkup done, in this way there are many features,
they have not yet made it available on the website that
how much money will be given for which thing and what are the details, but yes they
have definitely mentioned that this benefit can be up to 46,000 annually, so it
will be free of cost, for this you do not have to pay any additional premium,
let us understand the three options of this product, rides,
discounts and all the other benefits and features from the benefit illustration, the name of the plan is
ABC ABS LI Super Term Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited and here
a 35-year-old person whose name is Anil Rajpurohit is purchasing the policy,
his gender is male, he will pay the premium for 10 years, he
has taken the policy term for 40 years, where 18% GST will be applicable on the base premium, the customer
is a non-smoker, self-employed, has taken a cover of Rs 1 crore, where you
will get inbuilt waiver of premium on terminal illness and ATPD, which
is inbuilt, you do not have to pay any separate premium, here the option of depth benefit
has been taken in lump sum, 100% premium will come to ₹41,500, after GST it will come to ₹48,970,
I don't know when the government will come to its senses and will reduce the 18% GST a little on term plans,
many years have passed in waiting, but it is not happening till now
We hope that when GST will be reduced in future, your premium will also be reduced. We
can hope that this insurance cover is in front of your premium.
You can see the column of death benefit. Here you will see the maturity benefit as zero
but you will see the benefit of an early termination . After the completion of
your policy term of 30 years, you will see here, you will see an amount
of ₹4,15,000. Where will this come from? If you add your total premium of 10 years without GST,
then this amount will be with you. If you want to withdraw your money anytime after 30 years and except the last 5 years of the policy, or
want to close the policy, then you
can do that. If you see the rest of the surrender benefits in the policy, then you can also see the surrender benefit here.
If the policy has to be surrendered due to any reason, then you can surrender.
Let's see the second option. The name of the option is here, you will see the option of increasing cover.
Here your insurance cover will be in increasing order. Your base amount is one crore
and it increases to 2 crore. This insurance cover of yours will increase from 55 lakhs every year.
It will increase by 5% in an increasing order. But here I
wanted to ask a little from the product managers who are developing the product. If you have the answer, those who are
watching the video or the product management team, then
do tell us in the comment box. Here, the person who
is taking insurance cover of 1 crore from the first year, suppose there is death, he will get only one crore. Suppose there is death in the 10th year, then
he will get 1 crore 45 lakhs. And let's assume that the customer dies in the 25th year, then he
will get ₹2 crore. Now for this, the customer has to pay a premium of ₹14312 with GST.
In this premium, the customer can take an insurance cover of ₹crore from the first day and
can take it in the same plan of the same company. Let me tell you by example,
if the same customer takes insurance cover of ₹crore from the first day itself, then also his
premium will not exceed 1 lakh. ₹85,000 The premium is coming and if there is death
in the first year, even then it is ₹ crores, whether it is the fifth year or the 10th year, if there is death anytime, then it
is ₹ 2 crores, so why would anyone take the option of increasing when they know that in the beginning,
my insurance cover is not increasing for so many years and the premium
is also very high, so I did not understand the logic, if you understood, then definitely explain it to me,
now let's move towards the next option
which is called Level Cover with Return of Premium, here
the customer is purchasing insurance of ₹ 1 crore, here the premium
will be 61450, here the GST is 4.5% in the first year, then you will have to pay only 2.5% GST, now
18% will not be charged here because there is an option of return and premium, now
what is return of premium, you are seeing the column of maturity benefit, if
nothing happens to you during the entire policy term, then your total premium which you have paid is
returned to you, here you also get the surrender amount surrender value from the beginning If
you look at the column, a very large amount is visible from the very beginning, in the form of return on
premium, but its premium is a little more expensive than the pure term plan.
Now I will explain another option to you. Suppose the first option that I
told you was level cover, where the insurance cover was of one crore, where the premium
was coming to you around Rs 48,970,
but if the customer selects income here instead of death benefit lump sum and he
gets income for 240 months, if the nominee dies, then for the next 20 years he will get
Rs 4167 every month, if he gets monthly income, then his
premium here will be quite low, it will be Rs 39,000. So if a customer
is unable to afford a large premium, then he can also take the income option or if he feels
that a large amount has come and the family members cannot use it anywhere else or
cannot manage it properly, then you feel that for household expenses, ₹ 400 per month should come.
For the next 20 years, you can also take this option. If you want a big income, you
can take the amount of income for 10 years or 15 years, but there the premium
will increase a little. Here also you will get all the benefits of early exit.
Let
's talk a little about discounts. Like you saw that
the premium in level cover was ₹48,49,000, but if a female purchases the same policy
and if she is salaried, then she will get a discount due to salary and she will also get a discount
due to being a female, so her premium base premium would become ₹35,000.
After the first year discount, she would have to pay a premium of ₹37,000. Otherwise, you
have to pay a premium of ₹48,000 here. From next year also you will get ₹41,000.
Because a female is purchasing this policy, all other benefits will remain same as it is
final. Let's also see the riders, what are the riders, suppose they
are taking the customer level cover benefit only, but this time they
are taking accelerated critical illness benefit where they will get the benefit of 42 critical illnesses, they
are taking cover up to ₹1 lakh, now if any critical illness is diagnosed, they will get ₹1 lakh, later
whenever there is death, the family members will get the benefit of ₹1 crore - 10 lakh ₹90 lakh, this
accelerated critical illness benefit is available to you for only ₹3450 and this
premium will not increase for the next 10 years, so it is quite cheap, otherwise if you
want to take accidental death benefit cover up to ₹1 lakh, then you can get it for ₹7500,
hospital care benefit is also available for ₹2 lakh You are getting 2 lakhs, if you divide it by
250, you will get around ₹800 per day for surgical care, if you divide it by 50, then
you will get approximately
this, you can calculate it every day, there is a little mathematics,
I have explained the rest of the hospital care and surgery care in the ride race slide itself,
where how you will get the benefit in case of major surgery, how
you can get the hospital care benefit of ₹600 to ₹6000 per day, if you
want to increase the sum assured here, instead of 2 lakhs,
if you want to take 5 lakh, 10 lakh, ₹15 lakh, then you will get the benefit accordingly, maximum surgical care
will give you benefit up to ₹30,000 and maximum hospi care will give you benefit of up to ₹6,000 per day,
it is available at a very cheap amount of ₹450 If you
want to add it, you can add it to your policy.
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance already has three or four term plans
where their DG term plan is running, salary term plan is separate and right now they
have taken super term plan. So here I did a comparison with DG term plan. If
a 35 year old person is taking a policy term of 35 years and if
he is taking insurance cover of 1 crore, then what benefit will he get in the premium?
In which plan will you see more difference in premium? I
am not talking about the features, the features are different but if you look at the premium, then
the premium of both is same for 12 years, 15 years, 20 years or Paytm A60. There is not even a variation of 25 paise. But
if the premium payment is for 10 years or less, then you will get DG term plan a little cheaper.
If you are self-employed, then as per the eligibility criteria of the policy,
here a person from 18 years to 65 years can purchase this policy. If
you select the option of return and premium, then
a person of maximum age up to 55 years can purchase this policy. The minimum premium in this will be ₹25 lakh,
but when you go to purchase the policy, in most of the channels, it
starts from a minimum of 50 lakhs. You can also pay the premium regularly.
The option of limited premium pay is also given. In the return of premium, you
will get the option of 5 pay, 10 pay and 15 pay in limited pay, but if you purchase option one and option two, then you
will get limited pay options like 5 pay, 10 pay, 12 pay, 15 pay, 20 pay, P pay 60 in limited pay.
In this policy, you have been given many riders, in which
the rider of accidental death benefit is also given. You have also been given the rider of accidental death and disabilities,
which is generally available in every policy today in term policies.
Critical illness riders are also available, which I have told you about.
I have already explained that here you
are also given a surgical care rider where if there is a major surgery, you
can get a benefit of up to ₹ 000. Let's assume that you
have taken an insurance cover of ₹ 15 lakh for surgery care benefit and rider cover here, then if any major surgery happens, then you will get 50 times
of sum i.e. you will get almost ₹ 00 together in lump sum. Talking about
the hospital care rider benefit, here you
can get a benefit of ₹ 600 to ₹ 6000 per day. If you get admitted to the hospital due to any disease
and if you get admitted there normally, then you will get this benefit of ₹ 600 to ₹ 000.
Plus additionally you can get a benefit of ₹ 600 to ₹ 6000. If
the patient gets admitted in the ICU, then a separate benefit is available and if you are admitted for more than 7 days
, then you will get a benefit of ₹ 000. If you are admitted in a hospital for more than
3 days, you will get a lump sum amount of your daily cash amount separately. Loan
is not available in this policy because it is a term plan. Tax benefits are available under Income Tax Section 8.
You will get up to ₹1.5 lakh and the death benefit in 1010D is always tax free.
Talking about the surrender benefit in the policy, if you
pay regular premium, you will not get surrender benefit. In limited pay, you
will get surrender benefit. You will get the feature of RPO in the options of return of premium. In the policy,
grace period and free look period will be of 30 days for you and
you will get revival period of 5 years. There are some criteria for financial eligibility, I will tell
you , I will not be able to explain all of them in detail because there
are underwriting guidelines, but I will tell you about some good features
because in most of the companies, if the age of the person is between 18 years to 35 years,
then they get cover up to 25 times of their income, but
in this super term plan, if your age is between 18 years to 30 years, then you
will get cover up to 35 times of your business income or salary income, whatever your income is. For example, if your annual income
is ₹1 lakh and your age of death is 30 years, then you can take insurance cover of up to ₹5 crores
minus if you already have any insurance cover, then you can minus that much
insurance cover. You can see in the table on the side how much insurance cover
you can get for your annual income at different stages of life, at different ages.
So finally, if I summarize this plan, then this
is a very good term plan where you are getting health management services up to ₹46,000, that too
for free. Your premium may be ₹12,000, but you
can get health services up to ₹46,000 for free. Along with this, due to the inflation rate which
is happening every year, if you want to take the insurance in increasing order, then
the option of increasing is given to you for return and premium, but
the benefit of smart exit is already given to you after completion of 30 years. If you want to withdraw the money after this,
then you can take it. There are excellent riders. There
is a rider for hospital care, a rider for surgical care. You are also given the benefit of critical illness. There
is an inbuilt rider for accidental death benefit. Terminal illness and accidental
total and permanent disabilities riders are inbuilt features of pay and premium.
You do not have to pay any additional premium for this. You can pay limited pay. There
is an option of regular premium. You can also take the policy term for a long time.
You can take this insurance cover till the age of 85. If you want to take lump sum death benefit, you
can take it in income or you can take both income and lump sum. If you are in income, then you
also get a little cheaper premium. If you are salaried or female, then you
are also getting a little discount. So overall this is a very good plan. If you
want to purchase this plan from me, then you can contact me or
you can purchase the term plan by clicking on the link in the description. You can also purchase this one. You can do this and if
you want to compare other plans as well, like Aditya Birla's or even those of any other company, you
can compare and purchase them. If you liked the video,
please like and share my YouTube channel Anil Raje as much as possible, so that
you get to see all the insurance-related videos coming in the future, first of all.
Thank you so much, Jai Hind.